Hello English learners, welcome back to EnglishPod.
英语学习者你们好，欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And I'm Erika.
我是Erika。
And today we're going to be bringing you a great lesson about calling the office.
今天我们要给大家带来一堂关于打电话到办公室的精彩课程。
Yeah, that's right.
是的，没错。
So in this lesson, we're going to teach you some great words that you can use when you
所以在这节课中，我们会教你们一些有用的词汇，当你们
need to call your office to solve a problem.
需要打电话到办公室解决问题时可以用到。
Right.
对。
So, you are at home, you have a problem, maybe you can't go to the office, so you have to
所以，你在家，遇到了问题，也许你不能去办公室，所以你必须
call them and tell them that you're not going to be able to go.
打电话告诉他们你去不了了。
Yes.
是的。
So, we're not going to preview anything today because the dialogue is relatively easy.
所以，今天我们不会做任何预览，因为对话相对简单。
So let's listen to the dialogue for the first time and then we'll come back and look at
那么我们先听一遍对话，然后回来看看
some words.
一些词汇。
Hello, hey, Anil Day, Ekings Bay.
你好，嘿，Anil Day，Ekings Bay。
Aue, eimea, aealp, hei, ui, ee.
Aue，eimea，aealp，hei，ui，ee。
Aue, Anil Day.
Aue，Anil Day。
Uli Jay, ir hei.
Uli Jay，ir hei。
Aue, Uli Jay.
Aue，Uli Jay。
Aue, aealp, hei, ui, ee.
Aue，aealp，hei，ui，ee。
Aue, Uli Jay.
Aue，Uli Jay。
Actually, I'm eating, fei, aeq, hei, ee, lu, te, day.
实际上，我在吃，fei，aeq，hei，ee，lu，te，day。
I'm already say, ute, ir, hei, ate.
我已经说了，ute，ir，hei，ate。
Atwe, zang, rei.
Atwe，zang，rei。
I think, te, I'm, am, en, kei, aun, day, it, te, ho, te, lu, fei.
我想，te，I'm，am，en，kei，aun，day，it，te，ho，te，lu，fei。
I have, hei, ee, ere, kei.
我有，hei，ee，ere，kei。
Or, say, ho, te, ani, rei, oz, nei.
或者，说，ho，te，ani，rei，oz，nei。
And I'm eating, fei, light, li, sei, ir, sh, fei.
而且我在吃，fei，light，li，sei，ir，sh，fei。
I, ee, sei.
我，ee，sei。
O, sei, or, yei, auling, kei, and, ik, sei.
O，sei，or，yei，auling，kei，and，ik，sei。
Es, yei.
Es，yei。
I, uz, wei, open, hei, ute, ate, of, te, ik, ku, rei, rei.
我，uz，wei，open，hei，ute，ate，of，te，ik，ku，rei，rei。
O, kei, and, nei.
O，kei，and，nei。
I, trei, an, et, gei, aum, sei, es, trei.
我，trei，an，et，gei，aum，sei，es，trei。
All right, so a pretty easy dialogue, right?
好了，一个相当简单的对话，对吧？
Yeah, pretty simple.
是的，很简单。
All right.
好的。
So there are a couple of words that we want to look at.
所以有几个词我们想看一下。
So let's start with language takeaway.
那么我们从语言要点开始。
Language takeaway.
语言要点。
All right, well, today we're looking at three interesting words.
好了，今天我们来看三个有趣的词。
The first one is ouflay.
第一个是“ouflay”。
Ouflay.
“Ouflay”。
Marco, what is the ouflay?
马可，什么是“ouflay”？
All right, so when you have the ouflay, it means that you are sick.
好的，当你得了“ouflay”，意思是你生病了。
You have, it's very similar to a cold.
它和感冒很像。
Right, but just worse, right?
对，但更严重，对吧？
Worse, yeah.
更严重，是的。
So when you have the ouflay, it'll keep you in bed for a while, for maybe a week or two.
所以当你得了“ouflay”，它会让你卧床一段时间，大概一两周。
So you have a fever, your body is hurting.
你会发烧，身体疼痛。
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
对对对。
You're just, you're really sick.
你就是病得很重。
Yeah, you're really sick.
是的，病得很重。
Okay.
好的。
So, ouflay.
所以，“ouflay”。
All right, well, what about our next word?
好了，那下一个词呢？
Well, actually the next word is a phrase that you can use when you're calling the office.
实际上，下一个词是一个短语，你可以在打电话给办公室时使用。
Alin ke in iksei.
“Alin ke in iksei”。
Okay, this is a really useful phrase and I think it would help us to hear some examples
好的，这是一个非常有用的短语，我觉得听一些例子会帮助我们理解它的意思。
of what it sounds like so we can understand the meaning.
听听它听起来是什么样，这样我们就能明白含义。
Example one.
例子一。
Or fe iplpe ald ke in iksei ude te.
“Or fe iplpe ald ke in iksei ude te”。
Example two.
例子二。
If uye ald ke in iksei, ant one orme ayn te, or ye ayrd fe.
“If uye ald ke in iksei, ant one orme ayn te, or ye ayrd fe”。
Example three.
例子三。
Aymat ne iling fe aluwe, ose aym alin ke in iksei.
“Aymat ne iling fe aluwe, ose aym alin ke in iksei”。
So with this phrase, you're basically saying that you are not going to the office.
所以用这个短语，你基本上是在说你不会去办公室。
Exactly.
没错。
So let's take a look at our last word for language takeaway.
那我们来看看语言学习的最后一个词。
Ikovore.
“Ikovore”。
Okay, so it's a pretty simple word.
好的，这是一个很简单的词。
Ikovore means...
“Ikovore”的意思是……
To get better, to start feeling healthy again.
好转，开始恢复健康。
Okay, so kind of to recharge your batteries.
好的，算是给自己充充电。
Exactly.
没错。
So this is a great verb to use when you want to say I'm going to feel better.
所以当你想说“我要感觉好一点”时，这是一个很棒的动词。
Okay.
好的。
Ikovore.
伊科沃尔。
So some really great words, some really interesting phrases.
所以有一些很棒的词汇，一些非常有趣的短语。
So let's listen to this dialogue again and then we'll come back.
那我们再听一遍这段对话，然后再回来。
Hello, hey.
你好，嘿。
Anjelde Ikingspe.
安杰尔德·伊金斯佩。
Aujey, eime aayelp.
奥杰，艾梅·阿耶尔普。
Ahey Anjelde.
啊嘿，安杰尔德。
Ulijee irhe.
乌利杰·伊尔赫。
Ahey, uliejee.
啊嘿，乌利杰。
Aueyaayuhyee.
奥耶亚尤希。
Actually, I'm ilingfe ikwee alewute de.
实际上，我有点不舒服。
I'mare sei utee irhe evaluatee.
我有点发烧，需要评估一下。
Adwaysongre.
阿德韦松格雷。
I hencei amiment sensitivity honesy actinng high in a skill I am unable to penetrate and
我因此对敏感性诚实行动高度在一个我无法穿透的技能和工具上。
tools.
工具。
I'm eating fae, lightly say, Irish fae.
我在吃，轻描淡写地说，爱尔兰的。
I say, oh say, or yay, all in cayenne, ick say.
我说，哦说，或耶，都在卡宴，伊克说。
S yay, I us way, open hay, oo tay, ay tay, off tay, eek curry ray.
所以耶，我这么说，打开干草，哦塔，艾塔，奥夫塔，伊克咖喱雷。
Okay in nay, I tray, and at gay, I'm say, S tray.
好的，我尝试，然后在那，我说，S尝试。
Alright Marco, have you ever found yourself in a situation like this?
好的，马可，你有没有遇到过这种情况？
Well, yeah, a couple of times that I haven't been able to really make it to the office and I've had to call.
嗯，是的，有几次我实在没法去办公室，不得不打电话。
So yeah, I would have to call and tell them that I'm not going to make it or maybe that I'm going to be a little bit late.
所以是的，我得打电话告诉他们我去不了，或者可能会晚一点。
Alright, well, yeah, it happens to all of us and now you guys have all of this useful language next time you face this problem.
好的，嗯，这我们都会遇到，现在你们有了这些有用的语言，下次面对这个问题时就能用上了。
Exactly, so if you have any questions or comments, be sure to visit our website EnglishPod.com.
没错，所以如果你有任何问题或评论，一定要访问我们的网站 EnglishPod.com。
Marco and I are there to respond to your questions and comments.
马可和我会在那里回答你们的问题和评论。
As well, there are also lots of other great lessons for you to check out on the website.
另外，网站上还有很多其他精彩的课程供你们查看。
Exactly, so be sure to check out some of our first lessons. I'm sure you'll find them useful as well.
没错，所以一定要看看我们的一些早期课程。我相信你们也会觉得它们很有用。
Yes.
是的。
Okay.
好的。
Well, thanks for listening everyone and until next time.
好了，感谢大家的收听，下次再见。
Bye.
再见。
Music
音乐